ZACH HAYMORE

PROGRAMMER

DETAILS

PHONE

LINKS

LinkedIn

GitHub

SKILLS

Microsoft Office

.

Customer Service

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ

Java

• • • 0 0

Eclipse IDE

• • • 0 0

GitHub

• • • 0 0

HTML5

• • 0 0 0

CSS3

• • 0 0 0

SOL

• 0 0 0 0

PROFILE

Computer programmer and a potent written communicator that seeks to ask the right questions to strive for excellent job performance. A team player with management experience, project management experience, and job experience in nonprofit work, data mining, and architectural drafting. A current student pursuing a Postgraduate Certificate in Computer Programming from North Carolina State University with experience programming in Java.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Support Associate, YouthWorks

Remote

Sep 2020 — Nov 2020

- Supported the product development team through researching and developing three site trip products for the 2021 summer.
- Edited and wrote three product books that detail all facets and functions of each product site for internal summer staff usage.
- Utilized and updated CRM software to track relationships with community partners.

Associate/ Area Director, YouthWorks

Nashville, TN

May 2019 — Mar 2020

- Supervised, led, managed an area of three site managers and nines staff coordinators on the function, execution, and direction of each site for two months during the summer.
- · Performed performance evaluations on staff members under supervision.
- Wrote and edited educational documents that overview the history, vision, and function of six site products for both external and internal audiences.
- Coordinated the development of six site products through coordinating service opportunities for eight weeks out of the summer for 75 volunteers each week, networking relationships in six communities with site contacts, and finding educational, cultural, and community activities for customers to engage with the culture and history of each community.
- Created and wrote six product books that detail all facets and functions of each mission trip location for internal summer staff usage.
- Utilized and updated CRM software to track relationships with community partners and customers and their orders.
- Provided customer service to customers who purchased our products through phone calls, emails, call campaigns, and order inquiries.

Data Miner, Dauntless Discovery

Morrisville, NC

Oct 2018 — May 2019

- Analyzed and organized client's compromised data using document review software.
- Performed quality check inspections, analysis, and corrections to fellow employees' work.
- Operated Microsoft Office programs (Excel) to organize large quantities of data.

May 2018 — Aug 2018

- Supervised, led, managed three staff members on the function and operation of the product site.
- · Performed performance evaluations on staff members under supervision.
- Oversaw and performed all the administrative functions of the site by replying to emails from customers, filing finances and expense reports, and scheduling and facilitating meetings with customers, staff, and community leaders.

CAD Technician, Morelli Clinard Residential Designs

Rocky Mount, NC

Mar 2014 — Aug 2016

- Worked on and drafted Construction Documents for residential and commercial buildings using CAD programs (ArchiCAD and AutoCAD).
- · Helped train and prepare company trainees in using CAD programs.

EDUCATION

Postgraduate Certificate in Computer Programming, NC State University

Raleigh, NC

May 2020

- Created a project management Java application utilizing the State, Command, and Singleton Design patterns.
- Created a Java application that would be utilized by a coffee shop to track orders, a menu, and a catalog of customers through developing custom linear data structures.
- Developed a college course registration Java application through following the Software Development Life-cycle and OOP principals.
- · GPA: 4.0

BA in Global Studies, The College at Southeastern

Wake Forest, NC

Aug 2014 — Dec 2018

Graduated Summa Cum Lade with a GPA of 3.97

Certificate in Business Fundamentals, UVA McIntire Business Institute

Awarded with Distinction

Certificate in Sustainable Business, UVA McIntire Business Institute

Awarded with Distinction

ACHIEVEMENTS AND OTHER INFO

2018 Baccalaureate Colloquium for Research Writing

Wake Forest, NC

Won first place for Research Writing at the College at Southeastern.

Editorial Associate

Wake Forest, NC

Editorial Associate for the student-led SLAM magazine. Wrote blog posts and judged contests.

REFERENCES

References available upon request